A Guide to the Papers of the National Association of Pediatric Nurse Practitioners, 1972-1992
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- SERIES 1: Administrative Office Documents
  - Subseries: - Correspondence and Related Documents
    - Executive Director Mavis McGuire: Correspondence February - June 1991 (Box-folder 015-009)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including corporate funding, executive board meetings, Ellen Clore illness, bylaws revision, NCB certification exam, new NAPNAP officers, NFSNO Practice Committee, grant requests by NAPNAP
    - Executive Director Mavis McGuire: Correspondence July - October 1991 (Box-folder 015-010)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including conference and board meeting plans and agenda, criticism of NANP, opposition to DC increase of NP licensing fees, NAPNAP investments, requests for funding by NAPNAP, corporate support, legal issues of sending agenda information to NAPNAP post presidents, child care special interest group, 60 minutes segment on MSG, NAPNAP seal of acceptance requests
    - Executive Director Mavis McGuire: Correspondence November - December 1991 (Box-folder 015-011)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including NAPNAP finances, conference planning, NANP, corporate projects/ sponsors, NP/ PA pay differentials, 20th anniversary plans, cutbacks in corporate sponsorship, support of legislative favorable to NPs
    - Director of Membership and Communications: Correspondence January - December 1991 (Box-folder 015-012)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including increasing membership/ recruitment, Walk America, newsletter rating, chapter news for newsletter, corporate support, publicity, chapter involvement, NAPNAP pins, use of NAPNAP logo
    - Executive Secretary/ National Office Manager: Correspondence January - November 1991 (Box-folder 015-013)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including total NAPNAP CEU hours, membership labels use, Ellen Clore illness, NP practice issues, June board meeting, itemized publications distribution, investment policy, project proposal process, committee goals and effect on staff, student membership
    - Treasurer: Correspondence and Reports January - December 1991 (Box-folder 015-014)
      Re: NAPNAP budget and financial reports
    - Membership Committee: Correspondence, Long Range Planning Committee January - November 1991 (Box-folder 015-015)
      Re: Recruitment letters to PNPs, comments on long range plan
    - Nominations Committee: Correspondence January - December 1991 (Box-folder 015-016)
      Re: Candidates, elections, committee members, committee procedures and responsibilities, candidate recommendations, election process and documents
    - Program Committee: Correspondence January - April 1991 (Box-folder 016-001)
      Re: Conference presentations
    - Program Committee: Correspondence May - November 1991 (Box-folder 016-002)
      Re: Conference presentations, controversy over Procter & Gamble dinner presentation
    - Publications/ Public Relations Committee: Correspondence February - July 1991 (Box-folder 016-003)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including Poison Prevention Week, HIV Task Force, update on past presidents, NAPNAP publications update, update on Healthy Mothers Healthy Babies Coalition
    - Miscellaneous NAPNAP Committees: Correspondence January - November 1991 (Box-folder 016-004)
      Re: Objectives, membership of Long Range and Strategic Planning Committees, formation and proposed activities of Policy and Position Statement Committee includes copies of past position statements, Seal of Acceptance Protocol Committee, procedures review
    - 1991 Conference Correspondence February - December 1991 (Box-folder 016-005)
      Re: Conference planning, corporate support, conference program, comments on confer-ence, contest winners
    - NAPNAP/ McNeil Grants-In-Aid November 1990 - September 1991 (Box-folder 016-006)
      Re: Applications, evaluations of conference expenses, award winners, procedures
    - NAPNAP McNeil Scholarship August - November 1991 (Box-folder 016-007)
      Re: Applications and funded projects
    - Journal of Pediatric Health Care/ Mosby May - September 1991 (Box-folder 016-008)
      Re: Reader survey, editorial, board meeting minutes, charges for publication by Mosby, subscription rate
    - NP Degree Courses 1991 (Box-folder 016-009)
      Re: Listing of institutions
    - Henry K. Silver Award January - March 1991 (Box-folder 016-010)
      Re: Nominees, winner of NAPNAPs Silver Award for PNP accomplishments at national level
    - Sustaining Members January - November 1991 (Box-folder 016-011)
      Re: Solicitation of Sustaining Members, payment by sustaining members, list of sustaining members
    - NAPNAP PR Campaign/ Ketchum January - December 1991 (Box-folder 016-012)
      Re: Public relations campaign, report by Ketchum, press release on patients' and NPs' survey, preliminary results of survey
    - Special Projects January - November 1991 (Box-folder 016-013)
      Re: Immunization Education and Action Committee, Medical Device and Laboratory Product Problem Reporting Program, Practice Guideline Panel on Otitis Media, Poison Prevention Week, Kids Count Data Book, National Coalition to Prevent Childhood Injury
    - Corporate Projects: Procter and Gamble May - November 1991 (Box-folder 016-014)
      Re: Diaper Rash brochure, includes NAPNAP member's response
    - Maginnis and Associates Insurance June 3, 1991 (Box-folder 016-015)
      Re: Insurance for NAPNAP members
    - NAPNAP Task Force: Access to Care February - May 1991 (Box-folder 016-016)
      Re: Task Force review of access to care information, evaluation of ANA, AAP plans, formulation of NAPNAP position on health care access
    - NAPNAP Task Force: Access to Care May - December 1991 (Box-folder 016-017)
      Re: Task Force review of access to care information, evaluation of ANA, AAP plans, formulation of NAPNAP position on health care access, American College of Nurse Midwives invitation
    - NAPNAP Task Force: Access to Care May 1991 - October 1992 (Box-folder 017-001)
      Re: Immunization campaign and grant program, applications for "Shots for Tots" and "Give It Your Best Shot" grants, reports of use of grants, compare donations
    - NAPNAP Task Force: AIDS January - April 1991 (Box-folder 017-002)
      Re: Development of NAPNAP position on HIV testing of health care workers, client/ provider disclosure, transmission in invasive procedures, etc., CDC position, funding on AIDS research, AIDS panels and commissions
    - NAPNAP Task Force: AIDS May - July 1991 (Box-folder 017-003)
      Re: Development of NAPNAP position on AIDS issues, AIDS panels and commisssions, AHCPP Report on physicians, nurses and AIDS
    - NAPNAP Task Force: AIDS July - September 1991 (Box-folder 017-004)
      Re: - as previous two folders, ANA position on testing, CDC guidelines, legislation on testing, and exposure prone procedures
    - NAPNAP Task Force: AIDS October - December 1991 (Box-folder 017-005)
      Re: see previous 3 folders, grants available, CDC guidelines, AIDS legislation (testing), exposure prone procedures, and ANA positions
    - NAPNAP Task Force: Breastfeeding February - November 1991 (Box-folder 017-006)
      Re: NAPNAP participation in Breastfeeding Promotion Consortium
    - Miscellaneous NAPNAP Task Forces February - December 1991 (Box-folder 017-007)
      Re: Immunization Task Force - participation in drafting "Standards for Immunization Practices," Task Force on School Health - comment on AAP policy statement, work with AAP on school health issues, Children's Television Task Force - action for Children's Television Coalition, Task Force on Cost Effectiveness - NP cost effectiveness review
    - Associations: AAP/ NAPNAP February 1991 - March 9, 1992 (Box-folder 017-008)
      Re: NAPNAP participation on AAP Committee on Community Health Services, Virginia NAPNAP chapter and AAP relations, shared NAPNAP/ AAP legislative initiatives, participation in Children's First Coalition
    - Associations: AAP/ NAPNAP January - December 1991 (Box-folder 017-009)
      Re: NAPNAP input, disagreements with ANA's Statement of Standards of Clinical Nursing Practice
    - Associations: NANP/ NAPNAP January - October 1991 (Box-folder 017-010)
      Re: NAPNAP participation in NANP, NAPNAP priority issues and initiatives for 1991 - 1992, NP - PA distinctions, resignations from NANP, survival for NANP
    - Associations: NCB PNP/N/NAPNAP May - December 1991 (Box-folder 017-011)
      Re: Disagreement over BSN as certification criteria, facts about NCB for PNPs, NAPNAP participation on NCB Board, CEU tracking
    - Associations: NFSNO/ NAPNAP January 1989, January - September 1991 (Box-folder 018-001)
      Re: public endorsements of political candidates, NAPNAP participation in NSFNO, NFSNO comments on ANA Nursing Practice Standards
    - Associations: NOLF/ NAPNAP August - November 1991 (Box-folder 018-002)
      Re: NAPNAP participation in NOLF, NAPNAP participation on NOLF Maternal Child Council
    - Miscellaneous Associations: NAPNAP March - October 1991 (Box-folder 018-003)
      Re: NAPNAP participation on Immunization Education and Action Committee, nurse appointment to Joint Commission on Accreditation of HealthCare Organizations, work with North American Nursing Diagnoses Association, miscellaneous invitations and acknowledgement
    - NAPNAP Foundation January - December 1991 (Box-folder 018-004)
      Re: Foundation Board members, bylaws revision, donations to Foundation, grants process and procedures
    - NAPNAP Foundation January - March 1991 (Box-folder 018-005)
      Re: Grant proposals funded, rejected, reports on grant projects
    - NAPNAP Foundation March - June 1991 (Box-folder 018-006)
      Re: Grants approved and rejected, grant project reports
    - NAPNAP Foundation July - December 1991 (Box-folder 018-007)
      Re: grant project reports
    - Capitol Associates: AHCPR January - November 1991 (Box-folder 018-008)
      Re: Agency for Health Care Policy and Research, meetings, conferences, NAPNAP nominations
    - Capitol Associates: Miscellaneous Children's Issues January - October 1991 (Box-folder 018-009)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including Senate hearing on children and youth, Advisory Board on Child Abuse, Child Health Research Grants, National Commission on Children, Infant formula industry, WIC, Health Start initiative, infant mortality, School Readiness Act, Child Resistant Packaging and other safety issues.
    - Capitol Associates: Miscellaneous Children's Issues January - December 1991 (Box-folder 018-010)
      Re: legislation for child care funding and regulation, National Institute of Child Health and Human Development Coalition, automobile child restraints, miscellaneous women and children related legislation, World Summit for Children, UN Convention on the Rights of the Child, Child Health Day, Children's Day
    - Capitol Associates: Family Medical Leave January - November 1991 (Box-folder 018-011)
      Re: Legislation on family medical leave, NAPNAP support
    - Capitol Associates: Gag Rule, National Health Consortium January - November 1991 (Box-folder 019-001)
      Re: National Health/ Education Consortium, "Gag Rule" on family planning counseling
    - Capitol Associates: Immunizations/ Vaccines January - December 1991 (Box-folder 019-002)
      Re: Child immunization issues, nomination by NAPNAP of member to Advisory Commission on Childhood Vaccines, Immunization Education and Action Committee, National Vacinne Advisory Committee
    - Capitol Associates: Lead Poisoning March - December 1991 (Box-folder 019-003)
      Re: Alliance to End Childhood Lead Poisoning legislative activity
    - Capitol Associates: Malpractice January - November 1991 (Box-folder 019-004)
      Re: Medical liability reform legislation, National Coalition for Medical Liability Reform
    - Capitol Associates: Medicare/ Medicaid February - December 1991 (Box-folder 019-005)
      Re: Payment of benefits to nurse practitioners, legislation
    - Capitol Associates: National Practitioner Data Bank (Box-folder 019-006)
      Re: Proposed data expansion, support of ANA position on use of data bank, user fees
    - Capitol Associates: Nursing Education January - June 1991 (Box-folder 019-007)
      Re: Education funding legislation (Ind. Nursing Education Act), Advisory Council on Nursing Education, grant funding, Nursing Student Loan Program, NAPNAP and ANA testimony to Congress
    - Capitol Associates: Nursing Education June - December 1991 (Box-folder 019-008)
      Re: legislation, grant funding, National Health Service Corps loans, Nurse Education Reauthorization Act
    - Capitol Associates: Nursing Research January - November 1991 (Box-folder 019-009)
      Re: National Center for Nursing Research activities, redesignation, research funding, recent research studies, primary care research needs, NIH strategic plan
    - Capitol Associates: Nursing Shortage March - May 1991 (Box-folder 019-010)
      Re: Commission on Nursing shortage
    - Capitol Associates: Pediatric AIDS February - September 1991 (Box-folder 019-011)
      Re: Pediatric AIDS Coalition activities, AIDS research, support for legislation
    - Capitol Associates: Physician Payment Review Commission January - June 1991 (Box-folder 020-001)
      Re: level of payments to non-physician providers
    - Capitol Associates: Physician Payment Review Commission August - December 1991 (Box-folder 020-002)
      Re: payments to non-physician providers, includes testimony of nursing groups, including NAPNAP
    - Capitol Associates: Prescriptive Privileges March - September 1991 (Box-folder 020-003)
      Re: DEA rules affecting PNPs
    - Capitol Associates: Seat Belt/ Helmet Laws January - October 1991 (Box-folder 020-004)
      Re: Safety belt and motorcycle helmet legislation
    - Capitol Associates: Women's Health Issues, Food/ Supplements Regulations February - December 1991 (Box-folder 020-005)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including: Women's Health Equity Act, FDA and USDA regulations
    - Capitol Associates: Miscellaneous January - December 1991 (Box-folder 020-006)
      Re: Miscellaneous issues, including: NAPNAP Christmas greetings to Congress, state legislative agendas, Immigration Nursing Relief Act, National Health Service Corps, meeting with Division of Nursing Director, ProPAC (non-practitioner reimbursement)
    - Capitol Associates: Miscellaneous July - December 1991 (Box-folder 020-007)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including: National Nurses Week, Nurses Coalition for Legislative Action, NP job openings, National health Service Corps on NPs, APGAR stamp, miscellaneous advisory councils, legislative issues affecting NPs, including House Appropriations Bill
    - Capitol Associates: Miscellaneous January - December 1991 (Box-folder 020-008)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including: rural health initiatives affecting NPs, tobacco education, MSG, FDA position on promotion of drugs by physicians, FDA drug approval process, NPs as abortion providers
    - President Ellen Clare: Correspondence January - April 1992 (Box-folder 021-001)
      Re: Letters to and from Congress regarding legislation, NAPNAP committees, HIV testing in healthcare workers, difference between NPs and Pas, Medicaid coverage of NP services, "Murphy Brown," Past Presidents meeting summary, nomination of NPANAP members to advisory boards, commissions, by-laws changes
    - President Ellen Clare: Correspondence May - July 1992 (Box-folder 021-002)
      Re: Letters to and from Congress, officials in support of legislation, nominations of NAPNAP members to advisory committees and boards, thanks to employers of NAPNAP committee members and officers for their support, committee appointments policy, thanks to committee members and representatives, IBM reimbursement policy
    - Past Presidents Jonides, Mullins, and Clore: Correspondence February - October 1992 (Box-folder 021-003)
      Re: Solicitation of information for annual report, NAPNAP accomplishments 1991 - 1992, change in Executive Director job description, meeting topics, 25th NAPNAP anniversary, legislative issues
    - President-elect Margaret Grey: Correspondence January - July 1992 (Box-folder 021-004)
      Re: NAPNAP Special Interest Task Force, committee appointments and objectives, threat to NP practice in Indiana, Novak NCB appointment
    - President Margaret Grey: Correspondence July - August 1992 (Box-folder 021-005)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including: nominations of NAPNAP members to advisory board and commissions, report from NAPNAP representative to AAP Committee on School Health, committee goals, NAPNAP endorsement of Immunization Standards, NAPNAP Access to Care statement, support for breastfeeding, response to Wall Street Journal article comments on NPs and to Child Health Guide, role of NPs in immunization, the National Advisory Board of the Newborn Channel
    - President Margaret Grey: Correspondence September 1992 (Box-folder 021-006)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including: response to ANA Social Policy Statement, participation in Child Health Day/ Month, schoolbased clinics, changes in NP certification, committee appointments, NAPNAP reaction to COGME report, NAPNAP/ AAP breakfast plans and agenda, Executive Board meeting planning
    - President Margaret Grey: Correspondence October - December 1992 (Box-folder 021-007)
      Re: NAPNAP position on healthcare reform/ access to care, strategic plan, Coalition for America's Children, nursing education issues, nomination of NAPNAP members to advisory boards and committees, membership problems, PNP Week in Anaheim, California, president's taks and progress, disposable diapers, support of NFSNO on NP documentary, NAPNAP position on advanced practice licensure, school-based clinics position statement, minority recruitment, NAPNAP task forces, letter to President Clinton
    - Executive Director Mavis McGuire: Correspondence January - April 1992 (Box-folder 021-008)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including: child abuse prevention comments, solitation of corporate funding, Educational Needs Assessment Survey, NAPNAP seal of acceptance for products, NAPNAP positions on various issues, advertisement critical of NPs, board appointments process, Procter and Gamble payment of first year NAPNAP dues, meeting, committee invitations
    - Executive Director Mavis McGuire: Correspondence May - June 1992 (Box-folder 021-009)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including: NAPNAP seal of acceptance for products, termination of graduate nursing programs at California State Long Beach; NAPNAP response, collaboration with University of California San Fransisco, National Council of State Boards of Nursing on advanced practice, NAPNAP national office business matters, National Office report for executive board on office activities, procedures, and staff, NAPNAP acknowledgement of ANA Standards of Clinical Practice, new board members
    - Executive Director Mavis McGuire: Correspondence July - December 1992 (Box-folder 021-010)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including: position and policy committee, strategic plan, corporate sponsorship at meetings, new staff position for national office, finances, hearing on aging, school health study
    - Director of Membership and Communications January - December 1992 (Box-folder 021-011)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including: matters of interest to chapters, membership, administrative fees on members, PR campaign, use of NAPNAP slides and mailing list, 20th anniversary plans, NAPNAP practice setting statistics, requests for NAPNAP Seal of Acceptance for products
    - Executive Secretary, National Office Manager: Correspondence January - November 1992 (Box-folder 021-012)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including: certificates to committee members (listed), policies for publications committee, Staff and Executive Board credentials, Seal of Acceptance pro-tocol, NAPNAP resource list, dues amount changes, Brady Bill, McNeil Co. grants to NAPNAP, Continuing Education fees/ providers, meeting schedule, Executive Board votes on issues, publications report (NAPNAP publications orders)
    - Treasurer February - December 1992 (Box-folder 021-013)
      Re: financial reports and budget worksheets
    - 1992 - 1993 Executive Board, Staff, Resources List 1992 (Box-folder 021-014)
      Re: Resource list
    - NAPNAP Operations Manual June 1992 (Box-folder 022-001)
      Re: Operations Manual
    - Legislative Committee March - December 1992 (Box-folder 022-002)
      Re: Monitoring of legislative issues and providing updates to NAPNAP members, production of NAPNAP legislative update newsletter begins November 1992
    - Membership Committee February - November 1992 (Box-folder 022-003)
      Re: Recruitment letters, membership survey, goals
    - Nominations Committee January - July 1992 (Box-folder 022-004)
      Re: Candidates, election, objectives
    - Nominations Committee October - December 1992 (Box-folder 022-005)
      Re: Candidates, election process
    - Policy and Position Statement Committee April - December 1992 (Box-folder 022-006)
      Re: Development, updating of NAPNAP policy statements including childcare, corporal punishment, breast feeding, health care reform (access to care), child abuse, third party reimbursement, and continuing education
    - Program Committee March - December 1992 (Box-folder 022-007)
      Re: Specific programs, corporate sponsorship, committee goals, possible program presenters
    - Public Relations Committee May - November 1992 (Box-folder 022-008)
      Re: Goals, ideas from NAPNAP members, election of committee members, NAPNAP logo change, Presidential endorsement by NAPNAP, corporate exhibitors at conference
    - Strategic Planning Committee February - December 1992 (Box-folder 022-009)
      Re: Goals (which include communication, health policy and legislation, and education/ research with specific targets) and coordination of other committees in meeting goals
    - Miscellaneous Committees September - October 1992 (Box-folder 022-010)
      Re: Goals, members of issues and actions, continuing education committees
    - NAPNAP Seal of Acceptance June 1992 (Box-folder 022-011)
      Re: Protocol
    - NAPNAP Public Relations Campaign: Ketchum September 1992 (Box-folder 022-012)
      Re: Summary of Ketchum/ NAPNAP PR campaign and future plans
    - Membership Survey Results September 1992 and n.d. (Box-folder 022-013)
      Re: Membership Survey Results
    - Membership Statistics and Directory 1976 - 1993 (Box-folder 022-014)
      Re: New Members by year, retention rate, geographical distribution, totals by year, membership directory 1992
    - Sustaining Members January - December 1992 (Box-folder 022-015)
      Re: Renewal of old members, solicitation of new ones
    - Use of NAPNAP mailing list January - December 1992 (Box-folder 022-016)
      Re: Rental of NAPNAP mailing list by researchers, employers, AAP
    - Maginnis & Associates Insurance February 1992 (Box-folder 022-017)
      Re: Liability insurance for NAPNAP members
    - 1992 Conference correspondence January - March 1992 (Box-folder 022-018)
      Re: Conference planning, participation, agenda, programs, corporate sponsors
    - NAPNAP Distinguished Fellow Award December 1991 - May 1992 (Box-folder 023-001)
      Re: Applications, nominations, voting, winner
    - NAPNAP McNeil/ Grants-in-aid November 1991 - July 1992 (Box-folder 023-002)
      Re: Applications & evaluations of winners
    - Journal of Pediatric Health Care/ Mosby February - April 1992 (Box-folder 023-003)
      Re: Reader comments, Mosby survey market profile
    - NAPNAP Corporate Projects July - September 1992 (Box-folder 023-004)
      Re: Burroughs Wellcome antiviral kits, Procter and Gamble hospital videotape, Ross Labs infant formula
    - Special Projects January - September 1992 (Box-folder 023-005)